[
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of abortion?",
    "answer": "A. Gen 1 – all made in God's image;<br>Gen. 9 –shedding the blood of man;<br>Ex. 20/Num. 5 – though shall not murder;<br>Psalm 127 – children are a heritage;<br>Psalm 139/Jer. 1 – knitted me in my mother's womb;<br>Matt. 19 – Let the children come to me"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of adultery?",
    "answer": "A. Prov. 6; John 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of alcoholism?",
    "answer": "A. Eph. 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of anger?",
    "answer": "A. Prov. 29; Matt. 5; Eph. 4; Col. 3; James 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of anxiety?",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 34, 55, 138; Matt. 6; Luke 12; Rom. 8; Phil. 4; 1 John 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address assurance of salvation?",
    "answer": "A. Job 19 - My redeemer lives;<br>John 10 – good shepherd;<br>Rom. 8 – God's election;<br>Phil. 1 – he who began the good work;<br>2 Tim. 1 – saved us not according to works;<br>1 Peter 1 – power of God guards us"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the death of a loved one?",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 34 – God's eyes are on us;<br>John 11 – Lazarus;<br>Rom. 14 – live and die in Christ;<br>1 Thess. 4 – grieve with hope;<br>Rev. 21 – New Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of divorce?",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 5, 19; Mark 10; Luke 16; 1 Cor. 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of depression?",
    "answer": "A. Deut. 31; Ps. 23; Matt 11; 1 Peter 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the necessity of faith?",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 3 – propitiation received by faith;<br>Heb. 11 – without faith it is impossible to please him"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the necessity of repentance?",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 6 – Two masters;<br>Matt. 7 – Sin leads to death, obedience to life;<br>Rom. 6 – old self is crucified;<br>Heb. 10 – Remaining in Sin;<br>Luke 24 – repentance should be proclaimed;<br>Acts 2, 3, 17;<br>Mark 13 – Always be Prepared;<br>John 3 – Only Believers;<br>Joel 2/1 John 1 – God Will Forgive the Repentant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address forgiveness?",
    "answer": "A. Prov. 17 – whoever covers an offense;<br>Matt. 18 – Unforgiving servant (forgive from the heart);<br>Acts 10 – everyone who believes receives forgiveness of sins;<br>Eph. 4 – don't let sun go down on anger;<br>Col. 3 – forgive each other as the Lord has forgiven you;<br>1 John 1 – confess and we will be forgiven"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures would you turn to for a funeral?",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 23; 1 Cor. 5, 15; John 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the humanity of Christ?",
    "answer": "A. Incarnation: John 1;<br>Human Weakness: John 4;<br>Human Emotions: John 2, 11;<br>Human Experiences: Luke 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic of homosexuality?",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 19; Lev. 18; Deut. 22; Judges 19; Rom. 1; 1 Cor. 6; 2 Peter 2; 1 Cor. 6; Jude 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the topic hope in trial?",
    "answer": "A. James 1; 1 Peter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address marriage difficulties?",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 2 – Marriage was instituted by God;<br>Eph. 5 – Christ and the Church;<br>Matt. 12 – Being together vs divide;<br>1 Peter 3 – how to live together"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address miscarriage?",
    "answer": "A. Ps. 46; 55; 139; 147"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address racial reconciliation?",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address the omniscience of God?",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 139, 147; 1 John 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address worship attendance?",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 18 – where two or three are gathered;<br>Acts 2 – had all things in common;<br>Rom. 10 – faith comes by hearing;<br>1 Cor. 14 – assumption of the gathered church (prophesy builds up the church);<br>Col. 3 – gathered church assumed (admonishing one another; singing psalms, hymns, sp. songs)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address visitation of the sick",
    "answer": "A. Ps. 22, 23, 51; Is. 53"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What scriptures address loss of believing spouse",
    "answer": "A. 2 Cor. 12, Psalm 73, Phil. 4; John 11"
  }
]
